Bjørn Mathisen

224-622-8543 || thebcm27@gmail.com

Automation Engineer and Software Developer | Minneapolis, Minnesota

Summary

A QA and Full Stack C# developer with four years' experience in C# ASP.Net, database design, and backend development as a Software Developer and a Selenium C# QA Automation Engineer with expertise in manual and automated UI Testing, Automated Web API Testing and technical writing using Kanban and Agile.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

.Net: C#, C++, ASP.Net, .Net Core, MVC, MVVM Web: JavaScript, XML, WPF, TypeScript, Java

Database: MS SQL, Mongo DB **Automation**: Selenium, C.A.T.S., Postman, Cypress, Cucumber

Tools: Jira, Trello, Azure DevOps IDEs: Visual Studio, Rider, VS Code, Eclipse

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Softvision: Minneapolis, MN

July 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months) | Automation Engineer and Quality Assurance Engineer While working at Cognizant Softvision, a contracting agency I have been assigned many different clients and have helped them deliver their product goals on time with 100 percent code coverage in a variety of Agile and Kanban work environments. I have been responsible for writing manual and automated tests to test front end and backend code using Selenium, MAQS, C.A.T.S and PlayWright, and in my own time developed a working knowledge of the Cypress and Cucumber frameworks. Some of my clients include:

Client: TriZetto Provider Solutions

Automation Engineer

While currently on contract at TriZetto I am responsible for automation test case creation, execution, and reporting for their frontend healthcare software. These responsibilities require testing various API calls through Postman and UI elements through Selenium C# with the C.A.T.S Frameworks all while using the P.O.M programming design pattern.

Client: Trane Technologies Quality & Automation Engineer

While working at Trane Technologies I was responsible for manual and automated test case creation and execution for their point of sales portal. This required daily testing of various API and UI elements, the maintenance and reporting of existing bug reports, and analyzing existing workflows for bugs all while maintaining direct and continuous communication with developers and product owners to deliver 100 percent code coverage and a fast turnaround time on all QA tasks.

Andersen Windows: Minneapolis, MN

Jan 2021 – June 2021 - 6 Month Contract | **Software Engineer**

Worked within a small team using an Agile style workflow to take requests from Home Depot business owners to add products and making changes to existing products for their product catalog software's back end services using C#, and API endpoints. Each product would have individual unit tests prior to submitting to QA for quality assurance testing, whom we met with daily to ensure a quality testing of completed work.

Micro Center: Saint Louis Park, MN

Nov 2019 – Jan 2021 | Computer Service Technician

While working as a Computer Service Tech repairing computer systems, I also managed inventory, handled parts ordering, and delt with front end customers. In addition, I took initiative and wrote bash and python programs to help diagnose computers networking issues and corrupt windows installations to help repair the issues they were facing.

Martina Carter Entertainment: Chicago, IL

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019 - Freelance | Website Programmer

Worked with the client to design and build a custom website for their product presentation and booking software which was designed to display the client's image heavy product listings along with a dynamic calendar scheduler.

Zerma | Chicago, IL

Jan 2019 – July 2019 - Freelance | Data Analyst and Python Programmer

Constructed a SQL database and a Python web crawler to extract external and internal customer information to remove 100% of the inaccurate customer data, trimming down the data size from 45,000 non usable data points to 17,000 usable data points. Saving the clients corrupted customer records.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING (CERTIFICATIONS)

- Bachelors in Computer Science | Principia College | 2014-2018
- Toastmasters Competent Communicator | Gavel Club | 2014
- **Eagle Scout** "Eagle Scout" is not just an award; it is a state of being. It represents integrity and the ability to do hard work

LANGUAGES

• Language | English | Fluent